<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lisa Röttjers</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lisa Röttjers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Interests I mainly work on inference and analysis of microbial networks. My focus lies on emergent properties, such as hub species, modules and motifs. In addition to accurate detection of such properties, I want to better study microbial dynamics to learn how these properties arise.
Outside the lab, I enjoy gardening. My proudest gardening accomplishment is my seed-grown Musa velutina, or pink banana.
Education  PhD in Microbial Networks 2017 KU Leuven  MSc in Biology - Molecular Development and Gene Regulation - Cum Laude 2015-2017 Wageningen UR BSc in Molecular Biology - Cum Laude 2012-2015 Wageningen UR   Biography In 2017, I became a doctoral student at the lab of Karoline Faust.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conferences &amp; Talks</title>
      <link>/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talks/</guid>
      <description> 3 May 2019, RSG Belgium Student Symposium  A clustering algorithm for weighted ecological networks   24 April 2019, IAFP European Symposium Introduction to microbial networks  13 March 2019, workshop on microbiome research @ Utrecht University Interactive tutorial on microbial association networks  25 January 2019, Microbiota Data Analysis Workshop Lecture &amp; tutorial on analysis of microbial networks  13 August 2018, ISME 2017 Poster presentation  3 May 2018, Solvay Workshop Poster presentation  14 February 2018, Netherlands Annual Ecology Meeting Talk on data from upcoming work: From hairballs to hypotheses   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description> Can we predict keystones? Lisa Röttjers, Karoline Faust From hairballs to hypotheses - biological insights from microbial networks Lisa Röttjers, Karoline Faust  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publications/</guid>
      <description> Can we predict keystones? Lisa Röttjers, Karoline Faust From hairballs to hypotheses - biological insights from microbial networks Lisa Röttjers, Karoline Faust  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teaching</title>
      <link>/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/teaching/</guid>
      <description>You can find my teaching materials here. All material is available under the Apache-2.0 license; you are free to reuse and modify any content available. For my participation in workshops, please check the &amp;lsquo;Conferences &amp;amp; Talks&amp;rsquo;section.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>